<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<metadata>
	<idinfo>
		<citation>
			<citeinfo>
				<origin>County of Albemarle</origin>
				<pubdate>Unknown</pubdate>
				<title>Pantops Master Plan Comprehensive Plan Land Use Designations - Current</title>
				<geoform Sync="TRUE">vector digital data</geoform>
				<pubinfo>
					<pubplace>Charlottesville, VA</pubplace>
					<publish>County of Albemarle - Office of Geographic Data Services</publish>
				</pubinfo>
				<onlink>\\Cob_planning\Mapping\MAPPING\Comp_plan\shape\crozetMP_landuse_current.shp</onlink>
				<ftname Sync="TRUE">pantopsMP_landuse_current</ftname></citeinfo>
		</citation>
		<descript>
			<abstract>This dataset represents the official land use designations of Albemarle County's Pantops Master Plan, officially adopted in March 2008. This file reflects parcel geography current through end of the previous calendar year.

This file depicts what is on the officially adopted Pantops Master Plan Land Use Map. The Pantops Master Plan map has some unique land use designations, specific to the Pantops Master Plan and the Pantops (Neighborhood 3) Development Area. These unique designations are only found in the Pantops Master Plan Land Use Map.

Pantops Master Plan Definitions and Descriptions:

Greenspace - Sensitive environmental features including stream buffers, flood plain, and adjacent slopes. Typically only passive recreation will occur in these areas or greenway trails. Also includes open space areas that may be managed and owned by homeowners associations. 

Parks - Public and semi-public parks, greenways, and active recreation areas. 

Urban Mixed Use - Retail, commercial services, office and a mix of residential types based on the Urban Density land use category. This mixed use land use category is expected to have equal parts of residential and commercial uses.

Commercial Mixed Use - Retail, commercial services, office, hotel/motel/conference facilities, and wholesale uses with scale appropriate for Neighborhood and Community Centers. Secondary uses include Employment uses. Residential uses at Urban Densities may be allowed as secondary uses. 

Employment Mixed Use - Employment generators, including professional, business park, medical office, research &amp; development, laboratory, and professional service uses. Light Industrial uses may be considered where appropriate. Secondary uses include retail/service that is supportive of the employment uses and residential uses at Urban Densities. 

Neighborhood Density Residential - 3 - 6 residential units per acre with residential support uses and limited non-residential uses. Neighborhood Density Residential areas will primarily accommodate single family dwelling unit types as well as institutional uses such as places of worship, public and private schools, and early childhood education centers including day care centers and preschools.  Neighborhood Density Residential areas accommodate small areas of non-residential land uses on the scale of Neighborhood Service, to serve residential uses. This may include corner stores of less than 4,000 square feet; live/work units above office and/or retail; small office buildings with less than 20,000 square feet; and studios/cottage occupations. 

Urban Density Residential - 6.01 - 34 residential units per acre with support uses and some non-residential uses.  Urban Density Residential areas accommodate all dwelling types as well as institutional uses such as places of worship, public and private schools, and early childhood education centers including day care centers and preschools Urban Density Residential areas accommodate small areas of non-residential land uses on the scale of Neighborhood Service, to serve residential uses.  This may include corner stores, less than 4,000 square feet; live/work units above office and/or retail; small office buildings less than 20,000 square feet; and studios/cottage occupations

Institutional - Civic uses such as schools, fire stations, and libraries; hospital uses, and other public uses.

PLACES:

The Framework Plan map place-types and focal points or centers for those places in the Pantops Development Area:
	
Centers: are intended to be nodes of activity and the preferable distance from a neighborhood center to the edge/fringe area is ¼ mile, although in Pantops the edges may extend beyond the quarter mile distance. Neighborhoods that correspond to centers are illustrated on the Framework Plan map with dashed circles. Three center types are shown for Pantops to serve as focal points for neighborhoods:

CG- Civic Green: is primarily an urban open space (not just natural) that includes uses fronting on the center, multiple access points to neighboring residential or employment areas, design elements that provide a sense of arrival and civic presence. Civic Greens or urban open spaces are components of other center types in the plan, however the Civic Greens indicated on the Framework Plan are larger more natural areas and are intended to serve as parks:

State Farm Boulevard
Peter Jefferson Place
Glenorchy/Gazebo Plaza

NS- Neighborhood Service: is a cluster of mixed use buildings with Neighborhood-serving retail/service uses on the first floor, includes an urban open space adjacent to the mixed use buildings (see the description of Civic Center Green). These centers are intended to provide neighborhood retail uses such as a newsstand, small restaurant, bakery, convenience store without gas pumps, pharmacy/drug store, florist, small professional office, daycare/childcare, hair salon, other services, and small office space/live work units. Single uses with a building footprint over 10,000 square feet should be considered conditionally with an FAR (Floor to Area Ratio) of up to 0.5 permitted. The Framework Plan designates two Neighborhood Service centers in Pantops:

Avemore/Cascadia
Rivanna Ridge

C- Community: A retail/service mixed-use center that is anchored by a grocery store and contains additional retail/service and other commercial. Single uses over 25,000 square feet should be considered conditionally and an FAR of 0.65 to 1.00 are permitted. It is designed with multiple connections to surrounding residential and employment areas. It includes an urban open space and possibly recreation or civic element. The Framework Plan designates two Community Centers in Pantops:

Pantops Shopping Center (Core Community Center)
Luxor

Core: are areas of the greatest intensity and formal design, with up to an FAR (floor to area ration) of 1.50.  Unlike Crozet, the Core of Pantops is not an existing downtown, but an area of the greatest activity.  Pantops Shopping Center/Riverbend  is the only area which meets this description and which could also redevelop with features typical of a downtown.  The distance from this core area in Pantops to the edge of the Development area is approximately 1 ½ miles. This area will serve as the focal point for the entire Pantops Neighborhood. 

Districts are single use areas which contain uses which are very important to support an area.  Airports, single-use employment centers, and large single-use areas constitute districts.  Environmental features can also help to define a district.  There is only one district in Pantops:
	
Employment District- An employment district is designated in Pantops at the almost 65 acre State Farm Insurance offices.  Due to its size, it does not have a "center" and is not intended to given its characteristics and nearby mix of uses and other centers.  
Corridors are linear elements that connect neighborhoods and civic elements (and other sites such as districts) to each other.  Where corridors exist between neighborhoods, the Neighborhood Model envisions that they be conceived as civic elements.  Corridors can be man-made or natural and serve transportation requirements or exist as open space.  Open space corridors combine natural features such as rivers and stream valleys with man-made elements such as parks and golf courses to provide a significant infrastructure of open space throughout the Development Area.  Greenways can even link separate neighborhoods together through a series of hiking and biking trails.  Transportation corridors include light rail lines, bus corridors, parkways, highways, and pedestrian and bicycle trails.  The Rivanna River and Route 250 are corridors in Pantops.

Neighborhoods
The Pantops Master Plan has defined seven Neighborhoods of three neighborhood types, two corridors, and one district based on the recommended Place-Type components. Specific recommendations for each place are included in this section of the Master Plan document and the Pantops Place-Types Table provides additional information.

RIVANNA RIVER CORRIDOR:

The Rivanna River Corridor includes both the river and land adjacent to the river along Free Bridge Lane, south of Darden Towe Park, and around the Pantops Shopping Center to River Bend. It is shown on the Framework Plan as an overlay to underlying land use recommendations to stress river-orientation and uses. Where there is no underlying land use designation for development and for the remainder of the corridor of the river through Pantops, a linear park and trails are in development. The Parks and Green Systems Plan calls for several access points along the River and a trailhead (major access point) as a feature of the linear park in and around the Free Bridge and Riverbend portions of the park.

The following disclaimer applies:
[These data/digitized maps] are interpretations of the official Land Use Plan maps found in the Comprehensive Plan.  These maps interpret the generalized land use boundaries found on the Comprehensive Plan land use maps to the nearest parcel boundary, except for RA/DA boundaries which are consistent with Comprehensive Plan Maps.  This interpretation was made to simplify basic reporting and statistical analysis using this data.  Final determinations of the Comprehensive Plan land use designations should be based on the official land use maps found in the Comprehensive Plan.  Contact the Chief of Planning (Planning Division), Department of Community Development, for information/determination of land use designations. (Interpretations should only be made by Chief or Planning Division staff)

These Comprehensive Plan Area Land Use Designations are described in detail in the County's Comprehensive Plan.  The Comprehensive Plan is Albemarle County's most important document regarding growth, development and change. It establishes government policy to help guide public and private activities as they relate to land use and resource utilization. It is the basis for land development regulations and decisions (rezonings, special use permits), capital improvements (public projects such as schools, parks, libraries), transportation, environmental and historic resource protection initiatives, new county programs and decisions on the distribution of county budget dollars to a multitude of programs and agencies.

The Pantops Master Plan, an adopted part of the Albemarle County Comprehensive Plan, is intended as a general guide for future development and systematic change in the Pantops (Neighborhood 3) Development Area. The Comprehensive Plan is advisory in nature and, with its accompanying maps, charts and other supplementary information, it sets forth the County's long-range recommendations for the development of land within its jurisdiction. The Comprehensive Plan also serves as a guide for the development and implementation of the Zoning Ordinance. Development guidelines contained in the maps, charts and other supplementary materials in the Comprehensive Plan are intended as targets rather than specific requirements, consistent with the advisory nature of the document.</abstract>
			<purpose>The purpose of this dataset is to reflect the Land Use Designations of the County's different Comprehensive Plan Areas.  The County's Comprehensive Plan can then be used to gather further information about these designations.</purpose>
			<langdata Sync="TRUE">en</langdata></descript>
		<timeperd>
			<timeinfo>
				<sngdate>
					<caldate>20080301</caldate>
				</sngdate>
			</timeinfo>
			<current>publication date</current>
		</timeperd>
		<status>
			<progress>Complete</progress>
			<update>None planned</update>
		</status>
		<spdom>
			<bounding>
				<westbc Sync="TRUE">-78.460884</westbc>
				<eastbc Sync="TRUE">-78.424980</eastbc>
				<northbc Sync="TRUE">38.047881</northbc>
				<southbc Sync="TRUE">38.017552</southbc>
			</bounding>
			<lboundng><leftbc Sync="TRUE">11494185.999951</leftbc><rightbc Sync="TRUE">11504520.999950</rightbc><bottombc Sync="TRUE">3894074.789001</bottombc><topbc Sync="TRUE">3905113.249864</topbc></lboundng></spdom>
		<keywords>
			<theme>
				<themekt>None</themekt>
				<themekey>Pantops Master Plan</themekey>
				<themekey>Comprehensive Plan Areas</themekey>
				<themekey>Land Use Designation</themekey>
			</theme>
			<place>
				<placekt>None</placekt>
				<placekey>Albemarle County</placekey>
				<placekey>County of Albemarle</placekey>
			</place>
			<temporal>
				<tempkey>Current</tempkey>
			</temporal>
		</keywords>
		<accconst>None</accconst>
		<useconst>No warranty, expressed or implied, is made by GDS as to the accuracy of the data</useconst>
		<ptcontac>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntorgp>
					<cntorg>County of Albemarle/Office of Geographic Data Services</cntorg>
					<cntper>Damon Pettitt</cntper>
				</cntorgp>
				<cntpos>GIS Coordinator</cntpos>
				<cntaddr>
					<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
					<address>401 McIntire Rd</address>
					<city>Charlottesville</city>
					<state>VA</state>
					<postal>22902-4569</postal>
					<country>USA</country>
				</cntaddr>
				<cntvoice>434-296-5823</cntvoice>
				<cntfax>434-296-4012</cntfax>
				<cntemail>dpettitt@albemarle.org</cntemail>
				<hours>8:00 A.M. - 5:00 P.M.</hours>
			</cntinfo>
		</ptcontac>
		<native Sync="TRUE">Microsoft Windows 2000 Version 5.2 (Build 3790) Service Pack 2; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.2.6.1500</native>
		<natvform Sync="TRUE">Shapefile</natvform></idinfo>
	<dataqual>
		<logic>This dataset should not contain any logical inconsistencies pertaining to topology.</logic>
		<complete>Base data was derived from ...</complete>
		<posacc>
			<horizpa>
				<horizpar>Not Available</horizpar>
				<qhorizpa>
					<horizpav>0</horizpav>
					<horizpae>Not Available</horizpae>
				</qhorizpa>
			</horizpa>
			<vertacc>
				<vertaccr>Not Available</vertaccr>
				<qvertpa>
					<vertaccv>0</vertaccv>
					<vertacce>Not Available</vertacce>
				</qvertpa>
			</vertacc>
		</posacc>
		<lineage>
			<procstep>
				<srcused>C:\Documents and Settings\dpettitt\Desktop\METADATA_TEST\template_Y2000_orthobased.xml</srcused>
				<procdate>Unknown</procdate>
			</procstep>
			<procstep>
				<procdesc>Metadata imported.</procdesc>
				<srcused>C:\GIS-PLOTS-ETC\Grants\CAP_Metadata2002\metadata_templates\template_Y2000_orthobased.xml</srcused>
			</procstep>
			<procstep>
				<procdesc>Metadata imported.</procdesc>
				<srcused>C:\GIS-PLOTS-ETC\Grants\CAP_Metadata2002\metadata_templates\ortho2000_template.xml</srcused>
			</procstep>
			<procstep>
				<procdesc>Metadata imported.</procdesc>
				<srcused>C:\GIS-PLOTS-ETC\Grants\CAP_Metadata2002\metadata_templates\ortho2000_template_400scale.xml</srcused>
			</procstep>
			<procstep>
				<procdesc>Metadata imported.</procdesc>
				<srcused>C:\GIS-PLOTS-ETC\Grants\CAP_Metadata2002\metadata_templates\contact_template.xml</srcused>
			</procstep>
			<procstep>
				<procdesc>Metadata imported.</procdesc>
				<srcused>C:\DOCUME~1\JCHAMB~1\LOCALS~1\Temp\xml5E.tmp</srcused>
			</procstep>
			<procstep>
				<procdesc>Dataset copied.</procdesc>
				<srcused>Q:\MAPPING\Comp_plan\shape\compplan_landuse2006</srcused>
			</procstep>
			<procstep>
				<procdesc>Dataset copied.</procdesc>
				<srcused>Q:\OOMGAIR\Ty Chambers\compplan_landuse2006</srcused>
			</procstep>
			<procstep>
				<procdesc>Dataset copied.</procdesc>
				<srcused>Q:\MAPPING\Comp_plan\shape\compplan_landuse2006</srcused>
			</procstep>
			<procstep>
				<procdesc>Dataset copied.</procdesc>
				<srcused></srcused>
			</procstep>
			<procstep>
				<procdesc>Dataset copied.</procdesc>
				<srcused></srcused>
			</procstep>
			<procstep>
				<procdesc>Dataset copied.</procdesc>
				<srcused></srcused>
			</procstep>
			<procstep>
				<procdesc>Metadata imported.</procdesc>
				<srcused>Q:\MAPPING\Comp_plan\shape\compplan_landuse2006.shp.xml</srcused>
			</procstep>
			<procstep>
				<procdesc>Metadata imported.</procdesc>
				<srcused>C:\DOCUME~1\JCHAMB~1\LOCALS~1\Temp\xml16F.tmp</srcused>
			</procstep>
			<procstep><procdesc Sync="TRUE">Metadata imported.</procdesc><srcused Sync="TRUE">C:\DOCUME~1\JCHAMB~1\LOCALS~1\Temp\xml2DC.tmp</srcused><date Sync="TRUE">20080515</date><time Sync="TRUE">10294400</time></procstep><procstep><procdesc Sync="TRUE">Dataset copied.</procdesc><srcused Sync="TRUE">D:\Projects\CompPlan-LandUseMaps\Y2007LandUseUpdate\shp\pantopsMP_landuse2008</srcused><date Sync="TRUE">20080516</date><time Sync="TRUE">11032000</time></procstep></lineage>
	</dataqual>
	<spdoinfo>
		<direct Sync="TRUE">Vector</direct>
		<ptvctinf>
			<sdtsterm Name="pantopsMP_landuse_current">
				<sdtstype Sync="TRUE">G-polygon</sdtstype>
				<ptvctcnt Sync="TRUE">87</ptvctcnt>
			</sdtsterm>
			<sdtsterm>
				<sdtstype>String</sdtstype>
				<ptvctcnt>139</ptvctcnt>
			</sdtsterm>
			<sdtsterm>
				<sdtstype>G-polygon</sdtstype>
				<ptvctcnt>139</ptvctcnt>
			</sdtsterm>
			<sdtsterm>
				<sdtstype>Entity point</sdtstype>
				<ptvctcnt>139</ptvctcnt>
			</sdtsterm>
			<esriterm Name="pantopsMP_landuse_current"><efeatyp Sync="TRUE">Simple</efeatyp><efeageom Sync="TRUE">Polygon</efeageom><esritopo Sync="TRUE">FALSE</esritopo><efeacnt Sync="TRUE">87</efeacnt><spindex Sync="TRUE">FALSE</spindex><linrefer Sync="TRUE">FALSE</linrefer></esriterm></ptvctinf>
	</spdoinfo>
	<spref>
		<horizsys>
			<planar>
				<planci>
					<plance Sync="TRUE">coordinate pair</plance>
					<coordrep>
						<absres Sync="TRUE">0.000000</absres>
						<ordres Sync="TRUE">0.000000</ordres>
					</coordrep>
					<plandu Sync="TRUE">survey feet</plandu>
				</planci>
				<mapproj><mapprojn Sync="TRUE">Lambert Conformal Conic</mapprojn><lambertc><stdparll Sync="TRUE">36.766667</stdparll><stdparll Sync="TRUE">37.966667</stdparll><longcm Sync="TRUE">-78.500000</longcm><latprjo Sync="TRUE">36.333333</latprjo><feast Sync="TRUE">11482916.666667</feast><fnorth Sync="TRUE">3280833.333333</fnorth></lambertc></mapproj></planar>
			<geodetic>
				<horizdn Sync="TRUE">North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
				<ellips Sync="TRUE">Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips>
				<semiaxis Sync="TRUE">6378137.000000</semiaxis>
				<denflat Sync="TRUE">298.257222</denflat>
			</geodetic>
			<cordsysn><geogcsn Sync="TRUE">GCS_North_American_1983</geogcsn><projcsn Sync="TRUE">NAD_1983_StatePlane_Virginia_South_FIPS_4502_Feet</projcsn></cordsysn></horizsys>
	</spref>
	<eainfo>
		<detailed Name="pantopsMP_landuse_current">
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">Shape</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Geometry</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">0</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Land_Use</attrlabl>
				<attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">50</attwidth><attalias Sync="TRUE">Land_Use</attalias></attr>
			<attr><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">FID</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">FID</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">50</attwidth><attrdef Sync="TRUE">Internal feature number.</attrdef><attrdefs Sync="TRUE">ESRI</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom Sync="TRUE">Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom></attrdomv></attr><enttyp>
				<enttypl Sync="TRUE">pantopsMP_landuse_current</enttypl>
				<enttypt Sync="TRUE">Feature Class</enttypt><enttypc Sync="TRUE">87</enttypc></enttyp>
		</detailed>
		<detailed>
			<enttyp>
				<enttypl>Polyline</enttypl>
			</enttyp>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>FID</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Entity</attrlabl>
				<attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">50</attwidth></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Layer</attrlabl>
				<attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">14</attwidth></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Level</attrlabl>
				<attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">50</attwidth></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Color</attrlabl>
				<attrtype Sync="TRUE">Float</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">19</attwidth><atnumdec Sync="TRUE">11</atnumdec></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Linetype</attrlabl>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Text</attrlabl>
			</attr>
		</detailed>
		<detailed>
			<enttyp>
				<enttypl>Polygon</enttypl>
			</enttyp>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>FID</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Entity</attrlabl>
				<attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">50</attwidth></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Layer</attrlabl>
				<attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">14</attwidth></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Level</attrlabl>
				<attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">50</attwidth></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Color</attrlabl>
				<attrtype Sync="TRUE">Float</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">19</attwidth><atnumdec Sync="TRUE">11</atnumdec></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Linetype</attrlabl>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Text</attrlabl>
			</attr>
		</detailed>
		<detailed>
			<enttyp>
				<enttypl>Annotation</enttypl>
			</enttyp>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>FID</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Entity</attrlabl>
				<attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">50</attwidth></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Layer</attrlabl>
				<attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">14</attwidth></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Level</attrlabl>
				<attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">50</attwidth></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Color</attrlabl>
				<attrtype Sync="TRUE">Float</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">19</attwidth><atnumdec Sync="TRUE">11</atnumdec></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Style</attrlabl>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>FontId</attrlabl>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Text</attrlabl>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Height</attrlabl>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Angle</attrlabl>
			</attr>
		</detailed>
	</eainfo>
	<distinfo>
		<distrib>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntperp>
					<cntper>Damon Pettitt</cntper>
					<cntorg>County of Albemarle/Department of Planning and Community Development/Office of Geographic Data Services</cntorg>
				</cntperp>
				<cntpos>GIS Coordinator</cntpos>
				<cntaddr>
					<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
					<address>401 McIntire Rd</address>
					<city>Charlottesville</city>
					<state>VA</state>
					<postal>22902-4569</postal>
					<country>USA</country>
				</cntaddr>
				<cntvoice>434-296-5823</cntvoice>
				<cntfax>434-296-4012</cntfax>
				<cntemail>dpettitt@albemarle.org</cntemail>
			</cntinfo>
		</distrib>
		<resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
		<distliab>The information depicted in this GIS layer is the result of analyses performed on a variety of sources.  The accuracy of the information presented is limited to the collective accuracy of the sources on the date of the analysis.  The information is believed accurate and reasonable efforts have been made to ensure the accuracy of the data.  However, the County of Albemarle expressly disclaims responsibility for damages or liability that may arise from use of this data.  This product is the property of the County of Albemarle and its use is thereby restricted.</distliab>
		<stdorder>
			<digform>
				<digtinfo>
					<transize>0.492</transize>
					<dssize Sync="TRUE">0.232</dssize></digtinfo>
				<digtopt>
					<onlinopt>
						<computer>
							<networka>
								<networkr>Not Available</networkr>
							</networka>
						</computer>
					</onlinopt>
				</digtopt>
			</digform>
			<fees>$25.00 per distributable dataset, not to exceed $250.00 for a particular dataset</fees>
			<ordering>Submit request in writing (e-mail acceptable) stating who you are, what organization you are with (if applicable), what you will be using the data for, and agreeing to not resell the data to anyone.</ordering>
			<turnarnd>2 weeks</turnarnd>
		</stdorder>
	</distinfo>
	<metainfo>
		<metd Sync="TRUE">20110222</metd>
		<metc>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntorgp>
					<cntorg>County of Albemarle/Department of Planning and Community Development/Office of Geographic Data Services</cntorg>
					<cntper>Damon Pettitt</cntper>
				</cntorgp>
				<cntpos>GIS Coordinator</cntpos>
				<cntaddr>
					<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
					<address>401 McIntire Rd</address>
					<city>Charlottesville</city>
					<state>VA</state>
					<postal>22902-4596</postal>
					<country>USA</country>
				</cntaddr>
				<cntvoice>434-296-5823</cntvoice>
				<cntfax>434-296-4012</cntfax>
				<cntemail>dpettitt@albemarle.org</cntemail>
				<hours>8:00 A.M. - 5:00 P.M.</hours>
			</cntinfo>
		</metc>
		<metstdn Sync="TRUE">FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
		<metstdv Sync="TRUE">FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
		<mettc Sync="TRUE">local time</mettc>
		<metextns>
			<onlink>http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink>
			<metprof>ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof>
		</metextns>
		<metextns>
			<onlink>http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink>
			<metprof>ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof>
		</metextns>
		<metextns>
			<onlink>http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink>
			<metprof>ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof>
		</metextns>
		<metextns>
			<onlink>http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink>
			<metprof>ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof>
		</metextns>
		<metextns>
			<onlink>http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink>
			<metprof>ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof>
		</metextns>
		<metextns>
			<onlink>http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink>
			<metprof>ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof>
		</metextns>
		<metextns>
			<onlink>http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink>
			<metprof>ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof>
		</metextns>
		<langmeta Sync="TRUE">en</langmeta><metextns><onlink Sync="TRUE">http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink><metprof Sync="TRUE">ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof></metextns></metainfo>
	<Esri><CreaDate>20080516</CreaDate><CreaTime>11032000</CreaTime><SyncOnce>FALSE</SyncOnce><SyncDate>20110222</SyncDate><SyncTime>22121200</SyncTime><ModDate>20110222</ModDate><ModTime>22121200</ModTime><MetaID>{FCB66F64-14D3-4EEC-9234-BAD94C30CF9A}</MetaID><DataProperties><lineage><Process Name="FeatureClassToFeatureClass_3" ToolSource="C:\Program Files\ArcGIS\ArcToolbox\Toolboxes\Conversion Tools.tbx\FeatureClassToFeatureClass" Date="20081204" Time="114825">FeatureClassToFeatureClass Q:\MAPPING\Comp_plan\shape\pantopsMP_landuse_current.shp "C:\Documents and Settings\dpettitt\Desktop\Temp\CompPlanLandUse.mdb" pantops # "Land_Use Land_Use true false false 50 Text 0 0 ,First,#,Q:\MAPPING\Comp_plan\shape\pantopsMP_landuse_current.shp,Land_Use,-1,-1" # "C:\Documents and Settings\dpettitt\Desktop\Temp\CompPlanLandUse.mdb\pantops"</Process><Process Name="Dissolve_6" ToolSource="C:\Program Files\ArcGIS\ArcToolbox\Toolboxes\Data Management Tools.tbx\Dissolve" Date="20081204" Time="114917">Dissolve pantops "C:\Documents and Settings\dpettitt\Desktop\Temp\CompPlanLandUse.mdb\pantops_Dissolve" Land_Use # SINGLE_PART</Process><Process Name="FeatureClassToFeatureClass_7" ToolSource="C:\Program Files\ArcGIS\ArcToolbox\Toolboxes\Conversion Tools.tbx\FeatureClassToFeatureClass" Date="20081204" Time="115451">FeatureClassToFeatureClass "C:\Documents and Settings\dpettitt\Desktop\Temp\CompPlanLandUse.mdb\pantops_Dissolve" Q:\MAPPING\Comp_plan\shape pantops_diss.shp # "Land_Use Land_Use true true false 50 Text 0 0 ,First,#,C:\Documents and Settings\dpettitt\Desktop\Temp\CompPlanLandUse.mdb\pantops_Dissolve,Land_Use,-1,-1" # Q:\MAPPING\Comp_plan\shape\pantops_diss.shp</Process></lineage></DataProperties></Esri><dataIdInfo><envirDesc Sync="TRUE">Microsoft Windows 2000 Version 5.2 (Build 3790) Service Pack 2; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.2.6.1500</envirDesc><dataLang><languageCode Sync="TRUE" value="en"></languageCode></dataLang><idCitation><resTitle Sync="TRUE">pantopsMP_landuse_current</resTitle><presForm><PresFormCd Sync="TRUE" value="005"></PresFormCd></presForm></idCitation><spatRpType><SpatRepTypCd Sync="TRUE" value="001"></SpatRepTypCd></spatRpType><dataExt><geoEle><GeoBndBox esriExtentType="native"><westBL Sync="TRUE">11494185.999951</westBL><eastBL Sync="TRUE">11504520.99995</eastBL><northBL Sync="TRUE">3905113.249864</northBL><southBL Sync="TRUE">3894074.789001</southBL><exTypeCode Sync="TRUE">1</exTypeCode></GeoBndBox></geoEle></dataExt><geoBox esriExtentType="decdegrees"><westBL Sync="TRUE">-78.460884</westBL><eastBL Sync="TRUE">-78.42498</eastBL><northBL Sync="TRUE">38.047881</northBL><southBL Sync="TRUE">38.017552</southBL><exTypeCode Sync="TRUE">1</exTypeCode></geoBox></dataIdInfo><mdLang><languageCode Sync="TRUE" value="en"></languageCode></mdLang><mdStanName Sync="TRUE">ISO 19115 Geographic Information - Metadata</mdStanName><mdStanVer Sync="TRUE">DIS_ESRI1.0</mdStanVer><mdChar><CharSetCd Sync="TRUE" value="004"></CharSetCd></mdChar><mdHrLv><ScopeCd Sync="TRUE" value="005"></ScopeCd></mdHrLv><mdHrLvName Sync="TRUE">dataset</mdHrLvName><distInfo><distributor><distorTran><onLineSrc><orDesc Sync="TRUE">002</orDesc><linkage Sync="TRUE">file://\\Cob_planning\Mapping\MAPPING\Comp_plan\shape\pantopsMP_landuse_current.shp</linkage><protocol Sync="TRUE">Local Area Network</protocol></onLineSrc><transSize Sync="TRUE">0.232</transSize></distorTran><distorFormat><formatName Sync="TRUE">Shapefile</formatName></distorFormat></distributor></distInfo><refSysInfo><RefSystem><refSysID><identCode Sync="TRUE">NAD_1983_StatePlane_Virginia_South_FIPS_4502_Feet</identCode></refSysID></RefSystem></refSysInfo><spatRepInfo><VectSpatRep><topLvl><TopoLevCd Sync="TRUE" value="001"></TopoLevCd></topLvl><geometObjs Name="pantopsMP_landuse_current"><geoObjTyp><GeoObjTypCd Sync="TRUE" value="001"></GeoObjTypCd></geoObjTyp><geoObjCnt Sync="TRUE">87</geoObjCnt></geometObjs></VectSpatRep></spatRepInfo><mdDateSt Sync="TRUE">20110222</mdDateSt></metadata>
